TAYLOR BLOUNT PROGRAMMER / JOURNALIST / BARTENDER

Summary

A Web Developer with previous experience and perspective in editing and creating effective marketing content for clientele. Effective independently or in a team setting, having guided junior developers through individual projects. A Multi-Media Journalist adept at creating hard hitting journalistic content and one of a kind. A Bartender with a vast knowledge of craft and blended cocktails

Employment

Gearbox Solutions

Software Developer

· Maintaining and developing finical applications with Vue

- Developing back end architecture with Node JS
- Managing and deploying Kubernetes clusters

Two Bucks Bartender

· Creating craft cocktails

Come and Talk it Multi-Media Journalist

Reported on breaking news events across Travis County from on the ground or in the studio

- Interviewed subjects relating to various stories covered
- Created stories to be aired on the radio
- · Brought news worthy personas onto the show

Faust Media

Multi-Media Production Assassitant

- Maintained cameras and photo equipment
- Filmed various productions for the company
- · Ensured producers had correct information about locations and client requests
- Set photography
- Gained clients for media production

Buckwild

310 East 6th St May 2020 to May 2021 Security

- Checked IDs at the door to ensure only those of legal age could enter • Ensured bar had acquit supply of alcohol for sale
- Desecrated altercations between customers and removed combative customers from the bar

Bartender

• Served alcohol to customers

· Created blended cocktails

Lambda School

Remote Apr. 2019 to 2020 Team Leader

- Conduct stand-up meetings with up to 10 students to discuss problem solving strategies and facilitate a team like environment Manage DevOps for individual teams that are building web applications
- Conduct thorough code reviews for developers, providing insight and debugging
- Provide professional development opportunities for students, assisting in coding and algorithm practice scenarios

Next Inc.

Copywriter/Marketing Team

Miam Apr. 2016 to Fall 2017

May 2021 to Current

- Wrote sales copy for website Created advertisements and postings about products online to increase traffic to both storefronts and online sales
- Wrote a script that automated product posting for various websites

Projects

Apr. 2019 to July 2019

This project gives users a one-stop shop for quantifying the risks of natural disasters for a particular zip code in the US. It displays several layers of data, including different kinds of disasters and timeframes (present, predictions, etc.)

Tech stack: React | Node | Flask | PostgreSQL | Mapbox

- Served as Full Stack developer on a cross functional team of 7, featuring 3 data scientists and 4 developers
- · Created interactive map display of natural disasters in the U.S. incorporating historical and present information sourced by team's data scientists
- Wrote a back end server to handle data for the application

Feb. 2020 to Apr. 2020 A platform as a service to build a web store, upload designs, and create products, all while plugging into scalablepress.com to drop ship your product.

- Tech Stack: Next JS | Node JS | PostgresSQL Worked as both a project manager and a lead developer overseeing 6 web developers
 - Built integrations with Scalable Press's APIs
 - Oversaw the teams tasks and set milestones for the client

Aug. 2019 to Oct. 2019

An application brings local restaurants, and customers together by allowing businesses to showcase and advertise their delectable creations, while allowing customers to benefit from each others shared experiences via reviews, and ratings.

Tech stack: Ruby on Rails | React | Google Maps | PostgreSQL

- Worked along side Engineers at Weed Maps
 Worked as a developer on both the front end and back end aspects along side 7 others
- Utilized tools built by google to create an algorithm for accurately finding locations around the world
- Built an online ordering system so customers can order from restaurants using our application so it an be delivered to them

May 2019 to June 2019

A management tool that helps managers run daily stand-up reports asynchronously to maximize efficiency and let team members submit reports any time of day Tech stack: React | Express | 0Auth | PostgreSQL

- Focused on front-end development and assisted other developers in the creation of a dynamically changing database
- Inherited code structure and database through a legacy project, improving upon any bugs or needed features

Contact

■ blount3taylor@gmail.com

8136136703

• Austin, Texas

thirdeveclub

Education

Lambda School

Remote Oct. 2021 to Current

305 East 6th Street

May 2021 to Current

Various Locations Summer 2020 to Winter 2020

Various Locations

Spring 2021 to Summer 2021

Jan. 2019 to 2020

Web Development 2019

2016 to 2018

Hillsborough Community College

Skills

JOURNALISM

Interviewing

Gaining Sources

Reporting Investigation

Multi-Media

Videography

Photography

Social Media Management

BUSNIESS

Online Advertising

E commerce Web Development

Social Media Marketing

Sales

TECHNICAL

Python

Ruby

Ruby on Rails

Node Back-end Architecture

DevOps

Front-end Architecture

JavaScript Libraries

Git Unit Testing

CSS/SASS

React

Redux PostgreSOL

PHP

Kubernetes Docker

Vue

Wordpress